class BiologyDb {
  static List<Map<String, dynamic>> biologydbquestions = [
    {
      "question": "Where does photosynthesis primarily occur in plant cells?",
      "options": [
        "Mitochondria",
        "Nucleus",
        "Chloroplast",
        "Endoplasmic reticulum"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which molecule carries genetic information in cells?",
      "options": ["RNA", "DNA", "Protein", "Lipid"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which molecule carries genetic information in cells?",
      "options": ["RNA", "DNA", "Protein", "Lipid"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of the endoplasmic reticulum in cells?",
      "options": [
        "Protein synthesis",
        "Lipid synthesis",
        "Energy production",
        "Cell division"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question":
          "Which organelle is involved in detoxification and metabolism of drugs in liver cells?",
      "options": ["Golgi apparatus", "Lysosome", "Peroxisome", "Vacuole"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main function of the Golgi apparatus in cells?",
      "options": [
        "Protein synthesis",
        "Energy production",
        "Cellular respiration",
        "Modification and packaging of proteins"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question":
          "Which cell organelle is responsible for maintaining cell shape and providing structural support?",
      "options": [
        "Mitochondria",
        "Nucleus",
        "Cytoskeleton",
        "Endoplasmic reticulum"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary function of ribosomes in cells?",
      "options": [
        "Energy production",
        "Protein synthesis",
        "Lipid synthesis",
        "DNA replication"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary function of ribosomes in cells?",
      "options": [
        "Energy production",
        "Protein synthesis",
        "Lipid synthesis",
        "DNA replication"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "In which organelle does cellular respiration take place?",
      "options": [
        "Mitochondria",
        "Nucleus",
        "Ribosome",
        "Endoplasmic reticulum"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of the lysosomes in cells?",
      "options": [
        "Energy production",
        "Cellular respiration",
        "Breakdown of cellular waste and debris",
        "Protein synthesis"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question":
          "Which cellular structure contains the cell's genetic material?",
      "options": [
        "Mitochondria",
        "Nucleus",
        "Ribosome",
        "Endoplasmic reticulum"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    }
  ];
}
